Michael Longley papers, 1960-2000
Emory University
- Writings by Michael Longley, circa 1966-2001, Series 2; Boxes 16-43; OP1-4
  - Poems,circa 1968-2000, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 16-34; OP1-4
    - Collected poems, 1968-2000, Subseries 2.1a; Boxes 16-27; OP1-4
      - "Edward Thomas's War Diary" [variant titles: "And No More Singing," "Edward Thomas in the Trenches"] (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - "Ferry" (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - "Fleadh" (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - "Fleance" (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - "Flora" (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - "Fury" (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - "The Goose" [variant title: "The White Goose"] (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Granny" (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - "Halcyon" (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - "In Mayo" (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - "The King of the Island" (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - "Landscape" (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - "Last Rites" [variant titles: "Death-watch," "Drag-net"] (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - "Loamshire" (Box 19, Folder 27)
      - "The Lodger" [variant title: "The Opening Chapter"] (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - "Love Poem" [variant title: "Processes"] [See also Uncollected poems, "For a Self-Portrait" and "The Mole"] (Box 19, Folder 29)
      - "Man Lying On a Wall" (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - "Master of Ceremonies" [variant titles: Lionel, Uncle, Uncle George] (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - "Mole" [See also Uncollected Poems, A Question] (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - "Points of the Compass" [includes "Inscription," "Clapper Bridge," "Cell," "Standing Stone"] (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - "Riddles" [variant titles: "Double Barrel"] [includes: "Soft Target," "Sea-burial," "Leavetakings," "Stretch-marks"] (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - "Stilts" (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - "The Swim" [variant title: "Swimming"] (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - "Triptych" [variant titles: Birth; A Birthday] [includes: "Father" (The Sun’s Hair), "Baby," "Mother"] (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - "True Stories" [includes: "The Ring," "The Egg," "The Nest," "The Wren"] (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - "Weather" (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Man Lying On a Wall, notes and tables of contents (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Man Lying On a Wall, typescript [incomplete] (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Man Lying On a Wall, typescript [photocopy] (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - The Echo Gate (1979)
      - "Absence" [epigraph] (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - "Architecture" [variant title: "Buildings"] (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - "Ash Keys" (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - "The Barber's Wife" (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - "Bog Cotton" (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - "Botany" [includes: "Duckweed," "Foxglove," "Dock," "Orchid"] [See also Uncollected poems, "Nakedness"] (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - "Codicil" [variant title: "Codicils"] [includes "The Lamplighter," "Survivor," "Love Poem"] (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - "Dead Men's Fingers" (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - "The Echo Gate" (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - "Entomology" [includes: "The Wasp's Nursery," "The Dragonfly's Eye," "The Sundew's Menu," "The Butterfly Net"] (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - "Florence Nightingale" (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - "Frozen Rain" (Box 20, Folder 25)
      - "Grace Darling" (Box 20, Folder 26)
      - "Home Ground" (Box 20, Folder 27)
      - "Household Hints" (Box 20, Folder 28)
      - "Last Requests" [variant titles: "Newsreel," "The Kiss," "Buried Alive," Woodbine"] (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - "Linen Industry" (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - "Lore" [includes: "Cutting the Last Sheaf," "Fishing for Sand Eels," "Working the Womenfolk," "Bringing in the Kelp," "Ploughing by the Tail," "Finding a Remedy"] (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - "Martinmas" (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - "Mayo Monologues" [includes "Brothers," "Housekeeper," "Self-heal," "Arrest"] (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - "Meniscus" [variant title: "Hair"] (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - "Metamorphoses" [variant title: "Mythology"] [See also Uncollected Poems, "Dryad"] (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - "Mountain Swim" [variant title: "Bathe"] (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - "Obsequies" (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - "Oliver Plunkett" [variant title: "Oliver Plunkett's Head"] (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - "On Hearing Irish Spoken" (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - "On Mweelrea" (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - "Peace" [variant titles: "The First Arms Deal," "The Good Old Days"] (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - "The Rag Trade" (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - "Second Sight" (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - "Self-Portrait" (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - "Spring Tide" [variant title: "High Tide"] (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - "Sulpicia" [variant titles: "After Sulpicia," "Leaves From the Garland," "Torn From the Garland"] (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - "Thaw" [variant title: "Albino"] (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - "The War Poets" [variant title: "War Poets"] (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - "Wreaths" [includes "The Civil Servant," "The Greengrocer," "The Linen Workers" ["January 1976," "Elegy," "Massacre," "Near Whitebridge," "Teeth"]] [See also Uncollected poems, "The Student"] (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - The Echo Gate, notes and tables of contents (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - The Echo Gate, typescript with corrections (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - The Echo Gate, typescript [photocopy] (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - The Echo Gate, promotional blurbs (Box 21, Folder 24)
      - Patchwork (1981)
      - "Communications" [variant titles: "Bush Telegraph," "Double Image," "Long Distance," "Wire Tapping"] (Box 21, Folder 25)
      - "The Glass Iron" (Box 21, Folder 26)
      - Selected Poems, 1963 – 1980 (1985)
      - "Belfast to Dublin" [epigraph] [variant titles: "In memory of Brian O'Donnell," "Whose Round?"] (Box 21, Folder 27)
      - "Among Waterbirds" (Box 21, Folder 28)
      - "Hallowe'en" [variant title: "Turnip Head"] (Box 21, Folder 29)
      - "Light Behind the Rain" [variant titles: "Parts of the Body," "Windfalls"] [includes 1. Windfalls, 2. Eel [Elver], 3. Pimpernel, 4. Featherbrains, 5…., 6. Poppy, 7. Wren [St. Stephen's Day], 8…., 9.Barley, 10. Wake-house] (Box 21, Folder 30)
      - "Love Poem" (2) ["Orphans," "Twins," "Unborn"] (Box 21, Folder 31)
      - "The Love Poet" [variant title: "Love Poetry"] (Box 21, Folder 32)
      - "Maggie Moore's" (Box 21, Folder 33)
      - "Markings" (Box 21, Folder 34)
      - "No Man's Land" [variant titles: "For Isaac Rosenberg," "A Broken Wing"] (Box 21, Folder 35)
      - "On Slieve Gullion" (Box 21, Folder 36)
      - "Patchwork" [variant title: "Embroidery"] [includes "The Embroiderer"] (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - "The Power Lines" [epigraph to "New Poems"] (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - "Rune" [variant title: "Runes"] [See also Uncollected poems, "Geography"] (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - "Smoke in the Branches" [variant title: "History"] [includes: "The Disfigurement of Fergus," "The Grey of Macha," "The Bewilderment of Muircertach," "The Death of Mac Glas"] (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - "The Third Light" (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - "View" [variant title: "Returning to the Islands"] (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - "The White Butterfly" (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Selected Poems 1963 – 1980 [Wake Forest edition], notes and tables of contents (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Selected Poems, 1963 – 1980 [Wake Forest edition], page proofs with corrections (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Poems, 1963 – 1983, Introduction and TS of contents (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Poems, 1963 – 1983, promotional blurbs (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Poems, 1963 – 1983 [Gallery Press edition], galley proofs with corrections (Box OP2)
      - Poems, 1963 – 1983 [Gallery Press edition], page proofs (Box OP3)
      - Poems, 1963 – 1983 [Gallery Press edition], page proofs with corrections (Box OP4)
      - Poems, 1963 – 1983 [Penguin edition], wrapper (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Gorse Fires (1991)
      - "In Memory of My Parents" [epigraph] [variant titles: "In Drumbo Graveyard," "Winter"] (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - "An Amish Rug" (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - "Anticleia" (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - "Argos" (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - "Aubade" (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - "The Balloon" (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - "Between Hovers" [variant title: "In Memory of Joe O'Toole"] (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - "Blitz" (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - "The Butchers" [variant titles: "The Shankill Butchers," "The Suitors"] (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - "The Cairn" [variant title: "The Cairn at Dooaghtry"] (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - "Cathedral" (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - "Couchette" (Box 22, Folder 24)
      - "Detour" (Box 22, Folder 25)
      - "Eurycleia" [variant titles: "Lena, Returns," "Odyssey"] [See also Uncollected Poems, "The Maid"] (Box 22, Folder 26)
      - "Eva Braun" (Box 22, Folder 27)
      - "The Fireplace" (Box 22, Folder 28)
      - "Font" [variant title: "Holy Water"] (Box 22, Folder 29)
      - "Geisha" [See also Uncollected poems, "Madame Butterfly"] (Box 22, Folder 30)
      - "Ghetto" (Box 22, Folder 31)
      - "Glass Flowers" [variant title: "Marriage"] (Box 22, Folder 32)
      - "The Goldcrest" (Box 22, Folder 33)
      - "Gorse Fires" (Box 22, Folder 34)
      - "Halley's Comet" (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - "Hip-Bath" [variant titles: "Coalminer," "Miner"] (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - "Homecoming" (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - "Hummingbird" (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - "The Ice Cream Man" (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - "Icon" [variant title: "The Orphan"] (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - "Il Volto Santo" (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - "In Aillwee Cave" [variant titles: "The Cave," "In the Burren"] (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - "In a Mississauga Garden" [variant titles: "Meeting my Cousin," "The Ghosts"] (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - "In Memory of Charles Donnelly" [variant title: "The Olive Tree"] (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - "Insomnia" (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - "Jug Band" (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - "Laertes" (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - "Madame Butterfly" [See also Uncollected poems, "Geisha"] (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - "The Man of Two Sorrows" (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - "Mercury" (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - "Migrations" (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - "Northern Lights" (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - "Otters" [includes: "Above Corragaun," "At Allaran Point"] (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - "Peregrine" (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - "Phosphorescence" [variant title: "Venus"] (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - "Ponies" [variant title: "Pony"] (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - "Purlin" (Box 23, Folder 23)
      - "Quail's Eggs" (Box 23, Folder 24)
      - "Remembering Carrigskeewaun" [variant title: "Remembering Mayo"] (Box 23, Folder 25)
      - "Sea Shanty" (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - "The Shack" (Box 23, Folder 27)
      - "Stone-in-Oxney" (Box 23, Folder 28)
      - "Swallow" (Box 23, Folder 29)
      - "Terezin" [variant title: "Silence"] (Box 23, Folder 30)
      - "Trade Winds" [includes "Edenderry," …, "Carrickfergus," "Portavogie"] (Box 23, Folder 31)
      - "Tree House" (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - "The Velocipede" (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - "Washing" (Box 23, Folder 34)
      - "X-Ray" [variant title: "Skiagram"] (Box 23, Folder 35)
      - Gorse Fires, notes and tables of contents (Box 23, Folder 36)
      - Gorse Fires, TS (Box 23, Folder 37)
      - Gorse Fires, TS [photocopy] (Box 23, Folder 38)
      - Gorse Fires, page proofs with corrections (Box 23, Folder 39)
      - Gorse Fires, publisher's proof of paperback cover [Wake Forest press] (Box 23, Folder 40)
      - The Ghost Orchid (1995)
      - "For Janet and John Banville" [epigraph] (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - "Akrotiri" [variant title: "Volcano"] (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - "Autumn Lady's Tresses" [variant titles: "Dooaghtry," and "Lady's Tresses"] (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - "Baucis & Philemon" (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - "Behind a Cloud" [variant title: "Transfiguration"] (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - "Blackbird" (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - "The Camp-Fires" (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - "Cavafy's Desires" (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - "Couplet" (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - "Duach" (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - "The Fishing Party" (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - "Flowering" (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - "Form" (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - "The Ghost Orchid" (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - "A Gift of Boxes" [includes: "A Shiso Leaf," "Green Tea," "A Gift of Boxes," and "The Stone Garden"] (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - "A Grain of Rice" (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - "Gretta Bowen's Emendations" (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - "Headstone" [includes: "Spiral," "Blue-print" (The Ship of Death), …] (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - "Icicle" (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - "Kestrel" (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - "Massive Lovers" (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - "Oasis" (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - "A Pair of Shoes" (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - "Perdix" (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - "The Phoenix" (Box 24, Folder 25)
      - "Poseidon" (Box 24, Folder 26)
      - "River & Fountain" (Box 24, Folder 27)
      - "Rosemary" (Box 24, Folder 28)
      - "The Rules of Baseball" (Box 24, Folder 29)
      - "Sandpiper" (Box 24, Folder 30)
      - "The Scissors Ceremony" (Box 24, Folder 31)
      - "Sheelagh-na-gig" (Box 24, Folder 32)
      - "She-wolf" [variant title: "Lupercalia"] (Box 24, Folder 33)
      - "Ship of the Wind" [variant title: "Dutch Explorer"] [includes: "The Oars Heavy with Seaweed," and "Paradise Regained"] (Box 24, Folder 34)
      - "Sitting for Eddie" (Box 24, Folder 35)
      - "Snowhole" (Box 24, Folder 36)
      - "Sorescu's Circles" (Box 24, Folder 37)
      - "Watercolour" (Box 24, Folder 38)
      - "Water-lily" (Box 24, Folder 39)
      - "Wind-Farmer" (Box 24, Folder 40)
      - Love poems, elegies... [postscript], TS (Box 24, Folder 41)
      - The Ghost Orchid, draft associated with correspondence of 6 June 1995 (Box 24, Folder 42)
      - The Ghost Orchid, Longley's reading copy (Box 24, Folder 43)
      - The Ghost Orchid, notes (Box 24, Folder 44)
      - Broken Dishes (1998)
      - Broken Dishes, galley proofs (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Selected Poems (1998)
      - Selected Poems, drafts of contents and related material (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Selected Poems, incomplete draft (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Selected Poems, galley proofs [dated 8 April 1998] (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Selected Poems, galley proofs [dated 15 June 1998] (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Selected Poems, covers (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Out of the Cold (1999)
      - "Carol" (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - "A Lapwing's Egg" (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Out of the Cold, galley proofs [dated 24 July 1999] (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Out of the Cold, galley proofs [dated 23 August 1999] (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Out of the Cold, galley proofs [dated 14 September 1999] (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Out of the Cold, galley proofs [dated 4 October 1999] (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Out of the Cold, individual cards and related material (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - The Weather in Japan (2000)
      - "For Ronald Ewart" [epigraph] (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - "All of these People" (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - "The Altar Cloth" [includes "San Rocco"] (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - "The Beech Tree" (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - "Birds & Flowers" (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - "Bjorn Olinder's Pictures" [variant title: "Bjorn's Pictures"] (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - "The Blackthorn" [See also Uncollected poems, "Burren Prayer"] (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - "Broken Dishes" (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - "The Bullet Hole" (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - "Burren Prayer" (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - "A Can of Peas" (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - "The Cenotaph" (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - "The Choughs" (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - "The Comber" (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - "The Daffodils" (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - "Damiana" (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - "Design" (Box 26, Folder 20)
      - "The Diamond" (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - "An Elegy" (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - "Etruria" (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - "The Evening Star" (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - "The Exhibit" (Box 26, Folder 25)
      - "The Flock" (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - "Found Poem" [variant title: "Persephone"] (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - "Fragment" (Box 26, Folder 28)
      - "Garden" [variant title: "A Glimpse of Home"] (Box 26, Folder 29)
      - "The Hare" (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - "Heartsease" (Box 26, Folder 31)
      - "The Horses" (Box 26, Folder 32)
      - "The Hut" (Box 26, Folder 33)
      - "Invocation" [variant title: "The Paper Screen"] (Box 26, Folder 34)
      - "January 12, 1996" (Box 26, Folder 35)
      - "The Lapwing" (Box 26, Folder 36)
      - "The Latecomers" (Box 26, Folder 37)
      - "Leaving Atlanta" (Box 26, Folder 38)
      - "Leopardi's Song Thrush" (Box 26, Folder 39)
      - "The Level Crossing" [variant title: "Small Town"] (Box 26, Folder 40)
      - "Maureen Murphy's Window" [variant title: "Maureen's Window"] (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - "The Meteorite" (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - "The Moustache" (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - "The Musical Box" (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - "Night Time" (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - "Ocean" [See also Series 10, Seaman James Magennis] (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - "Pale Butterwort" (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - "Paper Boats" (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - "Pascoli's Portrait" (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - "A Poppy" (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - "A Prayer" [variant title: "The Vandals"] (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - "The Quilt" (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - "The Rabbit" (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - "Remembering the Poets" (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - "Scrap Metal" [includes "Lone Wolf"] (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - "The Seal" (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - "The Sewing Machine" (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - "The Shaker Barn" (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - "The Snow Leopard" (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - "A Sprig of Bay" [includes "The Mill"] [See also Subseries 2.7, Notebooks] (Box 27, Folder 20)
      - "The Sunburst" (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - "Sweetie Papers" (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - "A Touch" [variant title: "From the Irish"] [See also Subseries 2.7, Notebooks] (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - "The Vision of Theoclymenus" (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - "The War Graves" (Box 27, Folder 25)
      - "Waterburn" [variant title: "Phosphorescence"] (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - "The Waterfall" (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - "The Well at Tully" (Box 27, Folder 28)
      - "The Yellow Teapot" (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - The Weather in Japan, group of poems pinned together (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - The Weather in Japan, printer's proof (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - The Weather in Japan, annotated galley proofs (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - The Weather in Japan, revised galley proofs (Box 27, Folder 33)
      - The Weather in Japan, Michael Longley's reading copy [with notation of poems submitted for journals] (Box 27, Folder 34)
      - The Weather in Japan, notes and miscellaneous associated material (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Uncollected poems, circa 1968-2000, Subseries 2.1b; Boxes 28-34
      - Unpublished - proposed groupings of poems
      - Early Selected Poems content list (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Poems by Michael Longley, mimeograph copy (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Love Poems, 1963 – 1978 [photocopy] (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - The Hunters' Circle, New Poems, typescript [photocopy] (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - New Poems, typescript (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Green Places: Some Nature Poems Chosen by Michael Longley, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Translations, n.d., Selection of Translations dated 20 July 1995, and multiple translations of Ileana Malancioiu (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Other groupings of multiple poems [includes Dutch translations] (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Uncollected poems by Michael Longley
      - "Above Dooaghtry," TS (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - "Accident," TS (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - "Alfie Byrne" [variant title: "Black-out"] (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - "All My Own Work" [variant title: "Beachcomber"] (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - "Anatomy," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - "Anaximines" [variant title: "Anaximenes"] (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - "And Our Acquaintances," TS (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - "Anemone" (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - "Anglo-Irish" [variant titles: "The Big House in Recent Anglo-Irish Fiction"] (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - "The Animals," MS (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - "Antigone," TS (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - "Another," TS (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - "Armistice," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - "Ars Poetica (2)," TS (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - "At Home," MS (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - "At Killard" (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - "Aunts" (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - "An Autobiography," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - "Baby in Three Glimpses" [variant title: "Baby"] (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - "Bach," MS (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - "Bad Dreams," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 21)
      - "Baracuda" (Box 29, Folder 22)
      - "The Bay Tree," MS (Box 29, Folder 23)
      - "The Beech Tree," TS (Box 29, Folder 24)
      - "A Beginning," TS (Box 29, Folder 25)
      - "Beside the Seaside" (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - "Best Man and Bridesmaid," TS (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - "The Big House," [variant titles: "Rules of The House," "The Prisoner"] (Box 29, Folder 28)
      - "Biology" (Box 29, Folder 29)
      - "Bird in Space," TS (Box 29, Folder 30)
      - "A Birth" (Box 29, Folder 31)
      - "Blast," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 32)
      - "A Blessing," TS (Box 29, Folder 33)
      - "Bluebottle" (Box 29, Folder 34)
      - "The Blue Tits," TS (Box 29, Folder 35)
      - "Bomb," TS (Box 29, Folder 36)
      - "Bonfire" (Box 29, Folder 37)
      - "Booby-Trap" [See also Uncollected poems, "Punch-Line"] (Box 29, Folder 38)
      - "Boogie" (Box 29, Folder 39)
      - "The Bottle," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 40)
      - "The Bottle" (2), TS (Box 29, Folder 41)
      - "The Box," MS (Box 29, Folder 42)
      - "Briget's Cross," TS (Box 29, Folder 43)
      - "Broadcrown," MS and TS [variant title: "Milk in the River"] (Box 29, Folder 44)
      - "Bulk-Buying," TS [See also Uncollected Poems, "Lip Service" and "Punch-Line"] (Box 29, Folder 45)
      - "The Camp," TS [variant title: "A camp doctor speaks"] (Box 29, Folder 46)
      - "Carr's Loney," TS (Box 29, Folder 47)
      - "Cat's Cradle," TS (Box 29, Folder 48)
      - "The Celtic Twilight," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 49)
      - "Ceramics," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 50)
      - "Changes of Heart," TS (Box 29, Folder 51)
      - "The Chapters," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 52)
      - "Child of the Branches, MS and TS" [variant title: "The Mother's Lament"] (Box 29, Folder 53)
      - "The Children" (Box 29, Folder 54)
      - "Chorus" (Louis Armstrong's Hot Five), TS (Box 29, Folder 55)
      - "Christmas Eve" [variant titles: "Carol," "The Children"] (Box 29, Folder 56)
      - "Christopher's Third Christmas," TS (Box 29, Folder 57)
      - "Circus Elephant" [variant title: "Performing Elephant"] [See also Uncollected poems, "The Elephant's Nose"] (Box 29, Folder 58)
      - "The Coin," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 59)
      - "Collector's Piece" [See also Uncollected poems, "Lists"] (Box 29, Folder 60)
      - "Colotomy," TS (Box 29, Folder 61)
      - "The Compass," MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 62)
      - "Cong," MS and TS [variant titles: "Near Cong," "The Pool of Siloam"] (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - "The Contributors" (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - "Conversations" [variant title: "Fishing in the Sky"] [See also Uncollected poems, "Fishing in the Sky"] (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - "Cornelia" (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - "Cupid," TS (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - "Cuckoo-spit," TS and TS notes (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - "A Curlew's Feather" (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - "The Curse," TS [See also Uncollected poems, "Dryad [Naiad]"] (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - "Dark Glasses" (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - "Dates" TS (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - "Day of Dancing," TS (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - "A Dedication" (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - "The Devils (after Dante)" (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - "Dialect" (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - "A Different Moon (after Marin Sorescu)" (Box 30, Folder 15)